Welcome to localize in windows you ap apps using
...toolkit my name's camera alarm and I'm a senior program manager in the windows operating
system group and my name is frances joel I am a
senior program manager in the developer ecosystem platform team all right
...jump right in so the multilingual at toolkit is a program that is
...with visual studios...extension spin available since windows eight and we've
...it support the you ap platforms well since
...the go forward for windows ten the things that really gives you is
developers need to focus on writing code they don't really care about languages set for the
fact that the want to be multiple markets so the toolkit allows you to focus on
a writing your program managing your source language
...do the synchronization and translation services for you seamlessly works inside
a visual studio so-you in the environment that you love and your productivity and,
you also get instant access inside visual studio translation services such
as microsoft translator and microsoft professionally translated strengths.
So, you mean I get all...translation service for free
...developer you absolutely do so microsoft translator is a
service that microsoft charge for after a small free period and we give
all-you-can-eat for free with the microsoft translator wow that sounds great so
I have this application here ok.
And, this application...simple inc that I
role to demonstrate handwriting recognition in windows ten
thief so very nice I can write something lilac hello.
And, now recognizes into actual english text
...to say what's this application using the multilingual
or tool set of a can translate...any language I want for absolutely
free absolutely yes one hundred-percent free works in expressed addition as well and,
when you consider the scope of the windows marketplace we have a hundred and ninety
stores one hundred ninety market you can get into we have over sixty...the last
...member of payment model so the ability to charge for actually receive money from
...your customers is all built into the windows ecosystem having that in
their native language is really important for the value you can provide to the absolutely
...native...speaker right now let's make this...all right great let's do it all
...okay so we'll go ahead and...here.
And, I believe you have this project of already so we're going to switch to this project
now the toolkit is a free download off of the visitors
galleries and if you you've probably have a
...here so if you look we have version...out all right it's a
technical preview because this is one were review opry architected it so that
it works better with all the different environments and catch the other video
...across platforms...as well cool all right so we do have that pre installed active
installed it all you need to do this lecture project pretty much anywhere in the project that you want
and code your tools menu multiple up toolkit
then enabled so what does enable actually do that's a great question
what it really does enabling...so that the toolkit is
integrated with your project so now when you have you have your workflow when you run your
build it knows how to interact with your source resources such as your strings you have
in english and this and, translate them n pl them into chinese or at least
soon-to-be chinese gotcha okay so that's the...that really just sets the project
job now in order to add languages we simply say right click on it and
we say...toolkit which is your key maneuver everything you'll see there's a couple great out
once more...those a little bit but we wanted...language.
...goes off at this point and is query...that windows has available this is
...superset to what most people are going to use so you
...have a...like a really long list the...in fact if you have custom cultures
...cling...sports going on if you do the custom culture...on will show up here
too that's pretty funny so let's go and do chinese?
we just search for...here we go here's a chinese simplified.
Now you also have a couple of icons next to the name,
yeah,...this up those are the translation providers that are installed with the toolkit
by default so we provide...once recycling region that uses all of
microsoft's translations that we've used our products,
for example, all the translations from localized versions of word in windows
and exchange the role built-in the other
icon indicates the microsoft translator service and what does is you
have multiple translators providers so you can get the best of all
...so let's go ahead and add that?
...okay now we could select multiples but for this demo we're just going to pick the one
all right so I see the added a multilingual resources
and there's an x all aiff file underneath the folder what is an
xcel file a great question so...file is stands for ex
lift...industry-standard localization file reason...one-dot to in
this particular demo that is a metadata rich file that allows you to synchronized
source and targets each used by translation houses around the world so
privacy pretty much any translation vendor that is a real translation better knows how to run with this
ought to the thing we've done in this is different for role is we've created
your target res w file as well and this is how the system works is you manage
the resources in your x the file and we populate to your results file
...I...that way when you add a new string you never forget to
...it to the new language dot so I basically don't have to deal with the rest the rest of the following
...correct now you're just working on your source language in your programs features
...a convenient...that we think so
all right so there's many things we can do with this but really we...to do is we simply want to
So, like most...to do I just want to see what's going to look like chinese so
what's the finite show me how-to-do-it so simply just right click on your on your...file.
And, again, there's that multicultural kitten you'll notice a couple of their options are now enabled
...all enable now so just
...the generate machine translations sorry because like the right one air.
You know, it's a real demo when you have a failure like that right...go there we go so now
...going off to...online has a good things and I was going to have...online
...services...based upon the search strings in your project saying give me
the chinese simplified equivalent of these...not looks like is
doing pretty fast...we must have a good interconnection here today so, that's a good thing.
So, the green bars...complete you'll have...messy...tell you how many resources have been
translated in this case we have forty-six they've been translated ok so let's go ahead
run this project art so juice a deploying
we'll just we'll just to build and we'll start with a debugging all right there's going around.
Now notice all's I've done so far is that I want chinese and give you some translations
right you've already written the program right you've made a localize of all which is
...you should always make your programs localize well even if
...the us market think about the
...diversity for language and new york city
...several which here in seattle right and in fact the thing less than fifty
percent of the world's people speak english yes exactly it's
when you think about your market distribution remember that fifty percent.
Of the people that are going to run your application or more don't speak
english.
if you want them to run it make sure it's available in their language exactly right.
...building here a little bit.
Well, it's a pretty big project...the...
So, the other thing that the toolkit does for-you.
It makes it so that.
You really not worrying about translations you can get
high-end translations you can use the machine level translations
on using here but it really does get to the point of I
just need to develop my features
...have to worry about the rest all right so it's ok, this is english
...think happened here I'm not sure I guess my system locale ism sufficient chinese
yes so again windows understands look out your system so we ran the
program again on english computer we need to tell this computer to pretend that you're chinese
so...software and then we'll just...a few...locale over.
So, let's see just go to
...time and language...to language regions and this
...so on I change right go ahead and actually this pick are just...language should be find
...chinese as the default set us default okay.
And,...you program.
One of their this.
...use...didn't you moi.
Operandsso, okay, so, all the...nursing is
in chinese I switch my recognition to chinese online too.
Am great...nice chinese handwriting the up
so in just a few minutes we've taken a program written for
english market but that can support...the markets added chinese
...it enabled the windows handwriting recognition for
cheney's and now we have the same level function of this app for to markets
it's just feels like magic it feels like magic as quick as quick so this is the
value when you think about a hundred ninety markets and how long it took us just to get to
one additional market what would have taken if you did that manually?
Item though I probably go have to find song who speaks both english and chinese
do the translation at all strains the...work...take I've docile
hassle...I've done it with...of with a friend of mine who speaks russian who's really painful I didn't
have I hadn't written the...at that point...I had ok so there is some there is a problem here
that...some of these translation doesn't feel right I
mean it's okay but it just doesn't quite role author...yeah,
I'm not sure the spelling of the word clears correct...
So, let's go ahead and figure out what's going on with this for all right.
So, again, we are getting machine level translation quality and with machine level
is going to do its best guess based upon the context which we don't provide much context we
said...computers program try to match us up so it's not always going to get
A lot of cases this can be sufficient but you may want to go to a higher-level
...like since you're
you're native speaker we can have you just at the sorrell cricket so let's go ahead and coming
here and also we have to do is open of this file okay and we have a we have
a and editor that is a standalone editor and the reason why standalone is
you can send this program which is about a to megabyte download the...to friends and family
they install it and I'll show you how to do this but they can do the
...for incentive back for free all
the translation services the editor and now even your community has free tooling while the
...and I can bug my russian friends online and say hey
those some word doesn't seems writing help me...yes actually I know I know
developers that use twitter just say hey I can speak three languages I need six...help me of
these outrageous services and they get bombarded with the absolutely may help
...I can leverage...to this absolutely all right so let's
fix the were there I see it is right here, yeah,
how do I am ...what you can either edit directly just by...appear in the field...
hyping or let's find out if it has a better suggestion for us ok
so, on the top menu...a pretty is a pretty a streamlined editors on the menu
...have a translate option and a...you're right here the reason why translate is
great out is because this is...mark translate right so let's click on suggest?
And, let's go out and get the different providers so you'll see
...has these microsoft language portal that's all microsoft professionally translated strings
...which for some reasons says the word clear.
somehow in a system that got marked as they write translation all have to talk to someone about that because that
was actually does...everything else but here's your other...here's an image portals
...and...some...so you could like this one here...number
...the right that margaret you just go ahead and double-click
...chrysler's...suggestion and now we have fixed cool now if you
...the post edit you could just come up here and start typing again right so if we save this
okay.
And, then go ahead and close and this is runner program again.
what you could do with this also while waiting on this is on these menus
probably...because we're building media we have the ability to export
and import the translationsand, we also have a clear which I'll talk about
...moment what those...is those...ability to send to
...external party my russian...her this
x the file should have translated into russian...in the editor
...sent back and...I would import back in that way she can make that I can machine
...and she can fix the machine translations so I can continue to
develop washes localize...this and when they come back and it will match-up the strings
they have not changed...five change strings I...just...the file that automatically
mergers...for-you...the chancellors liberal...right exactly and
always make sure the right thing it has a multiple logic in it about a
...string is better than one that knees reviewing so always take a translate over that
so you don't have to worry about that and,
you just continue...you can do almost like revision review control
...is...that's really convenient...rather...project
ok so if I were to do spanish, for example, which is
...the same process so let's go ahead and do spanish only this time what
we'll do is we'll go through and will paren like we're going to send it off to
a spanish-speaking rent so how...that all...program?
And, we just simply adder languages again and again it's just the right click.
Multiple up toolkit error language.
An seizure...type the...since I...is that...to go hunt for it
...a lot...this is one thing new windows...you'll...is
the regions of the languages have been...adding extended...that...actually see with
this a great example you'll see that we have different providers because we don't have a good provider for this one
and we only have an exact match to spanish for the language runs
machine translations fallback.
...ad spanish and.
And, then we just write click instead of send generate machine...math sorry.
The such...on the radio instead of generate machine translations.
We simply just say I want to export them and I can
select multiple files I could even do it on multiple projects which is a little,
you know, a lot of data for one person but now simply just one...to an email.
I want...and exif I could says...common delimited but then our
...doesn't work for commodore omitted so common...is when...look like...I need in this format
...it gives you that flexibility I consented...compressed file from
...multiples make it really easy but here's the following send somebody okay this and this one off...will bring up
you email client...in this case we have outlook will have the file attached...have
...description about what you want...so gives me the download location
for tools that yes so this is the download location for tools...right here?
And, if they click on this.
Will take them directly to the visual should galleries cool and
they download now the key to remember here when you're talking to your
localized friends they don't need to words that they don't have visual studio even those
...a visual extension because this is an and I msi install
...only installed the pieces that it means
...see they don't have visual studio and not installing those components
...editor translation services...even was just that the can already at the
...file and change all the update all the translations they will be able to do
everything we did here except run in visual studio all I guess I don't need to run...visual
...that...exactly,
exactly so okay so I'll go ahead and?
Go ahead
...someone...save this file off of me do it this way.
...want to say these changes were not going to...of.
So, if I had actually synthesize off to a friend and,
I don't...prepped to propped the machine for it...do this real quick.
Quick a quick demo of.
...so I'll go ahead and copy this file and...going to put upon directory.
Directors for the sake...just have no place to
poured in from an open this up as a as my friend would
...a double-click it just runs the editor yes and I'm just going to
say translate all and I'm doing this for the demo sake because
...don't speak spanish so now what I can do is I can pretend that this file will
...import file and we'll see that I get my spanish translations
...friend received ...downloads the toolkit
...even she gets a free translation service you...doesn't want
to go through everything and...herself that's exactly right it's a great starting point because
now they can get our best guess and then go hey that was really close
and this one...change the whole thing the other thing that we're not going to really
...today is the translation providers are extensible so-if you
want-to do anything with different providers and like heaven forbid you do get google translate
right you could write your own provider to work with google...
yes it's api we've written complex project sure exactly how-to-do-it and,
it will then show up in your project and if it supports language you
can icon to represent your support that's very cool it's very clear we tried that we try to make it
is flexible as possible so if you had your own local db as well it would work just with
...on the machine would need internet access we're going to...save this.
And, go back to
work project and this file here doesn't have any translations in...so I'm go ahead and import these.
And, I'm going to go up one.
Where I put that file there is?
And, now I'm going to import this file into this project
this option for enable recycling ones or...recycling is
when it's not an exact match but we think it's a good fit.
In our case we...strict
...evaluate...if...want to be but this means that if my languages match in my
...during matches I don't care about the context don't care if it's the same resource id
all go ahead and pull...so it gives us the ability to take other projects we've
had translated and import them into this project that is unrelated as long as we have the same
...for example,
how many times you want to really look localize the...cancel...never
again right so I'm go ahead and import on this and also
...report that I have forty-six resources that were successful
in warmed so now if I do a if I do a quick build on this?
And, you'll see as a build you'll see that actually...are spanish files well
okay and it will now popular spanish file and we won't run the demo but
will show the resources now we have spanish cool so all the took
...what two three minutes
...better language I like to joked if you give me ten clicks I'll give you ten languages
...and it's not really joke moi.
Okay.
So, that's pretty much it for the for the demo that I love I love the how the
app just you can just read it and it can get your native language and translated into
the actual text format that's very useful for any type of application you...right and,
now you can take that all your markets where all the windows markets all the our windows and the our of
your language and that's pretty close to the entire world to the entire
world yes there's a lot of data on I've had developers tell me,
yeah, I found you...an I localized and for a particular market
and double my downloads right I love hearing that right if anybody has
...multi-lingual at microsoft-dot-com email to me I love this type of
stories because that's what we're trying to trying to make your life easy
in your translations with so you can get to the markets you want to get too especially since the
...american now is feud when it comes smart devices absolutely,
absolutely so here's the here's the rows w file for spanish
and you see that we have all...spanish translations...so we won't bother
...demo but, it would just show up in spanish if we set the machine locale like we did chinese
...do your spanish and recognition as well very cool all right.
So, I'm going to jump into a couple of questions that I was get developers are always going okay
...really great but, you know, I don't know anything about localization of
globalization and I'm like well that's fine because there's a lot of data out there on it.
So, this jump into that.
So, I'm going to be mystified some things so one of the things that people always
say is what I don't understand the globalization api...they're confusing.
They're actually pretty straightforward if you take a little time...some great examples if you
...time to look at it...about ensuring that the format of the
data are represented has the right commas decimal points
...of currency symbols on like
example if I show if I show any type of numeric value in france I'm
...get comma separator and I'm not always of the same location
english so if you use your decimal for matters your
...your currencies from the number format api as...just give those
to for free you pass the number it will do the right thing based upon your locale so
just call the right api...work for you just called...guys don't hard code
...code...you know,...dot format because that will just make...so you get bugs and people
...it doesn't make any sense...thousand should be...hundred because the commas neurons right ...
day for matters there's so many you so many ways to do time in the wrong
...the system api you'll get it right because it provides a
pattern so with the pattern you can say that I want the...the year and the day
it will based on locale how to order properly so it makes sense for that...
Instead of hard coding positions you have a pattern and it works really well and,
of course calendar right you don't ever try to write your own calendar to...it also does you know,
not everything is a growing calendar not everything starts on sunday as the first...week holier
...problems right so you use the canada controls on the system definitely some of the things to
avoid...talked about this a little bit this stream format for months
a year works really well and almost nowhere.
So, just don't use it ...you might be
...go over here in the states but it won't work anywhere else and,
the formatting this year's going to be wrong currency, you know, the dollar sign up for
the us dollar would possibly be offensive if you try to go to
multiple markets and if you event...with...app they're probably not going to run it exactly
even the diversity the market dover read the users language locale.
Unless there's a really good reason to and they have opted into it sometimes
as a valid reason to do it but when you do it remember...permanent they have to
unstable or you have to manually...back it...stuff ll so
that looks like a harmless api is a really powerful one but when used incorrectly you're going
...negative feedback icy and we know how much...your app now they have to screws
...system exactly, yeah, they well they have no way to undo it...but,
they can always on install you that's not something that's not what we're trying to promote
...of uses one with caution if you use it at all and...of course we talked about the
...controls just use the ones that are built-in you can't go wrong.
Localization...mystified these are these are some of
the core questions I get on localization as well.
Always use localization files for your for your strings.
Even if you're only going to a targeted market there are several applications I know of that
are that are centric to a particular market but they've made it look
liable and they go into other markets just because it might be fun for those markets...they get a high percentage
...from was markets I hope I have one called finger spell it actually gets a fifty percent download
...the us and it is an american sign language...it's like a unexpected
windfall it's and it's a planned windfall overt.
Four-ten clicks...right exact right.
Remember your strings are going to
grow frame a lot of lot of people actually translate source language in german and
go-to english just for this to avoid this becausegerman...and russian are going to be longer strings
...halts right and,
the toolkit orcas that if you want to...german work-related english we support that
...just great but just remember give growth room if you pack everything really tight
especially with all the...form factors it's not going to be a good user experience.
Very simple do your bindings your x you id in your store apps and if you use
and javascript apps make sure you do your...data...resource that just...up in your good to
go never...resource string manually by saying I'm just going to use
...string here because even if an exception go ahead and use the resource
loader api to get the strength of one note on that this will return
...string if it's not in your system so right here if resource loader dot
...string my resources doesn't exist in your rest avi file you could a blank so-if
you have length...looked here I didn't translate something I didn't create a string that
a creative ninety-four and then you know,
in your cultures for your images make sure that if you have images that are specific
to locale you put them in a path that has the path...image locale
...image that you want for the name path and that will make the system pick it up automatically so if I was
in chinese I...a background...showing my chinese image format background instead
of my us image which gives you that extra feels like it was built here right roaches
...stars...ratings right localization is not just for strains
correctness for other resources as well...and globalization is an issue display on the
...store...neutral display local axle.
And, a...resources that are available to developers go
over these pretty quickly so of course the multilingual up toolkit because I think everybody wants at least
and languages...cliques right now so, that's a real easy download
...on the link you have provided here we talk about what we do in the toolkit on
...blog take comments and feedback we also have a user work-site because those
are so cool I love when people give us feedback and use
...foresight because it will allow us to modify the product...give what they're looking for
...translation services these are the two we actually showed in the product so we have the
microsoft resource are the microsoft translator that is a pay for service unless
...the multiple up toolkit min which then we give you all-you-can-eat for free but if you want to integrate into a
website this is a great way to do it for dynamic website transmission and,
also the language portal is the microsoft professional
translated strings you can hook into that yourself as well we do it for with the toolkit.
And, of course localization samples right there you can never get enough localization sample success the
best way to learn so here's some basic ones that have your date your time formatting that is
pretty much ninety percent of the issues people hit download some of
the samples and play with it and you'll figure that out right away got our numbers
for...for example, you know, you just don't want to do to string on a number...the time you want to build put
...format and of course there are some...
samples on a full application for the localization aspect of a such as...with mapped.
That's our world winter of the multilingual up toolkit
...thank you very much for you for that app that that's an awesome app thank you and I'm looking for
dasi and cheney's and...all right thank you very much thank you.